むった
(六太)は…派手なネクタイですね｡
Th-This tie is a little flashy...
(ＡＤ)ん？よく似合ってますわよ｡
うふっ｡
It looks very nice.
ミスター･ナンバ 入れます｡
Mr. Nanba is coming in.
(オジー)やあ ムッタ
決まってるじゃないか｡
Hey, Mutta... You're looking sharp.
オジー…あんま変なこと
言わない…でよ｡
Ozzy,
don't say anything weird...
わかってるさ｡全国ネットだ➡
I know that. We'll be on national TV.
正直に私が見たままを話すよ｡
I'll just tell them exactly what I saw.
タイミング よろしく｡
It's time. Please head in.
(田沼)半数以上 沢木君に票が
集まったというのに…➡
Over half the members have voted for Sawaki,
まだ やりますか？
so why insist on continuing?
ほしか
にむら
星加さんも二村君も
どうして そこまで➡
Hoshika and Nimura,
why do you favor Nanba?
なんば
南波君を推すんですか？➡
個人的な感情でもあるんですか？
Are there personal reasons?
You shouldn't let personal emotion affect the astronaut selection process.
大事な飛行士の審査に
私情をはさまないでいただきたい｡
情をはさむなってんなら
パソコンにでも決めさせりゃいい｡
If you want to leave emotion out of the equation,
you could let the computers decide.
(星加)人を選ぶのは結局
｢情｣の部分でしょう｡➡
When we choose people, we rely on emotion.
私は南波君と仕事がしたい
と思いました｡
I want to work with Nanba.
だから彼を推すんです｡
That's why I'm pushing for him.
(職員)星加さん！➡
Hoshika!
大変です！南波君が…｡
Big news!
Nanba has...
南波六太君が アメリカで…｡
Nanba Mutta...
in America...
どうした？
(職員)六太君が今 テレビに！
What is it?
Mutta is
currently on TV!
Space Brothers
Ah
This feels so good, different from usual
I have no idea what's going on
It feels so good
I never understand what's going on around me
Nothing makes sense to me
Full of questions
Feel so moon
I danced with you in a desert lit by the moon
I won't lose to the rabbit and fly high
I'll fly high
#08 Smoky Heaven
The brother of astronaut Nanba Hibito, famous for his UFO sighting claims,
[TV](ﾆｭｰｽｷｬｽﾀｰ)
ＵＦＯ発言などで有名な あの➡
ひびと
南波日々人宇宙飛行士の実の兄
南波六太さんが➡
Nanba Mutta is currently attracting a lot of attention in America.
今 アメリカで
大きな話題になっています｡
…なんだ こりゃ｡
What's going on?
We're only alive because of his courage and wit!
[TV]彼の勇気と判断力のおかげで
我々は生きている！
[TV]ムッタが我々を
助けてくれたんだ！
Mutta saved us!
[TV]あ いや…俺は別に…｡
Er, I didn't do anything special...
[TV]とにかくスゴかった！
He was incredible.
[TV](ﾆｭｰｽｷｬｽﾀｰ)
消火器男を捕らえ
市民を救ったのは なんと➡
The one who captured the fire extinguisher man, and saved the day,
日本人宇宙飛行士ヒビト･ナンバの
お兄さん…ミスター･ムッタ｡
was Japanese astronaut Hibito Nanba's older brother, Mr. Mutta.
事件当時 唯一目が見えていた
というオジー･スミスさんに➡
The only witness able to see through the smoke, Ozzy Smith,
その一部始終を
語っていただきます｡➡
will recount the incident for us.
まずは 監視カメラに映っていた
決定的瞬間の映像を➡
First, let's begin with some images caught on security camera.
解説していただきましょう｡
おおげさ
《頼むから あんまり大袈裟に
言うなよ オジー｡➡
Seriously, don't exaggerate anything, Ozzy.
あ～まいったなぁ こんなことに
なっちまうとは…》
Man, I had no idea this would happen.
(司会者)それでは ＶＴＲどうぞ！
Then, let's play the clip.
え～まず ここ
右下に映っているのが犯人だ｡➡
So, the man sitting at the bottom right table is the culprit.
客になりすましている｡
He's pretending to be a customer.
ムッタは この男を見た時すでに➡
Mutta mentioned that he looked like a criminal the moment he first saw him.
｢犯罪の臭いがする奴だ｣と
言っていた！
《え そんなこと言ったっけ？
言ったか？あ 言ったな！》
Er, did I? I did?
I must have.
ここで男は突然 立ち上がり
店員や我々に➡
Then the man suddenly stood up, and began using his fire extinguisher on the customers, including us.
消火剤を噴射してきたんだ｡
そして…｡
And then...
男がレジに向かって１分後…
ここだ！
A minute after the man headed toward the cash register...
There!
ヒーロー ムッタが
果敢に男に立ち向かう！➡
Our hero, Mutta, bravely sets off to dispatch the villain.
低姿勢で若干ふらついてるのは➡
He's crouching and moving slowly because he can't see a thing.
消火剤で目が全く
見えてないからだよ｡
[VTR](強盗)な…何やってる お前！
動くな！
Wh-What are you doing?!
Don't move!
ここでムッタは機転を利かせ
何やら日本語で➡
This is where Mutta uses his wits. He yells something in Japanese,
強烈な言葉を浴びせ
いかく
犯人を威嚇したんだ！
to startle the criminal.
[VTR]あっ！ヤバイって！
[VTR](強盗)な…なんだ!?
Hey, that's dangerous!
What?
そして！
And then...
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
目が見えてないにもかかわらず
犯人に猛突進した！
He rushes the criminal, despite not being able to see a thing!
[VTR](強盗)やめろ！あっ！
[VTR](ガンッ！ゴン！)
画面からはみ出して映ってないが
私は見てた！
I'm not on screen here, but I saw everything that happened.
Mutta used a diving headbutt on the criminal!
この時 ムッタは犯人に
ダイビングヘッドバッドを➡
おみまいしたんだ｡
まるでサッカーの➡
It was like a header in soccer!
ヘディングシュートのようにね！
みなさん！今 ムッタさんは
弟 ヒビトさんと同じ➡
Everyone!
Mutta is currently working to become an astronaut, like his brother Hibito!
宇宙飛行士を目指してるんです｡
今頃 ちょうど宇宙飛行士達は➡
The astronauts are now engaged in blindfolded training,
｢目隠し訓練｣というのを
やっている｡➡
目が見えなくても まわりの状況を
把握している必要があるんだ｡
because they must remain aware of their surroundings, even when they can't see.
ムッタさんは これと同じ事を
今日 実践でやってのけた！
Mutta was able to demonstrate this ability in a real-life situation!
彼の記憶力と冷静な判断力…
そして➡
His memory, cool judgment, and courage
勇気のおかげで彼らは
救われたんです！
were what saved the day!
(観客)ムッタ！ムッタ！ムッタ！
Mutta! Mutta! Mutta!
《なんてこったよ この国は…➡
Something's seriously wrong with this country...
勝手に どんどん
盛り上がっちゃってよ｡➡
They're getting excited over nothing.
違うんだよ みんな
ほんとは全然 違うのよ｡➡
You have it all wrong!
The truth is completely different!
あの時 俺は…》
(観客)ムッタ！ムッタ！
I was actually...
((ぶはっ！ぺっ ぺっ))
俺は あの時 冷静どころか
めちゃくちゃパニクっていた｡
I was totally freaked out.
《まずい…殺される！》
This isn't good. He's gonna kill me!
《逃げよう！》
I should run for it.
(六太の声)俺は 本当は１人で
逃げようとしていた｡
I was trying to escape by myself...
《すまない みんな｡後できっと
助けが来るからね！》
Sorry, everyone!
I'm sure help will arrive eventually!
しかも 実は割と目も見えていた｡
And I could actually see pretty well.
《見つからないように低姿勢…
あっ！》
Keep low, so he can't see me...
Wh-What are you doing?
((何やってる お前｡動くな！))
Don't move!
《見つかった～！んっ!?》
He found me!
《何やってんだ？アポ！》
What are you doing, Apo?!
Hey, it's dangerous!
Don't go over there, Apo!
《そっちへ行くな！このアポ！》
((な 何だ!?))
Wh-What?!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
I could see fine.
(六太の声)目は見えてたくせに
目の前は真っ白で➡
But there was only white smoke ahead of me!
頭ん中も真っ白だった｡
And my mind was filled with white smoke.
Hey, what is this thing?
Stop it!
((うわ！おおお…
うわ～っ あ～っ！))
And Ozzy just happened to see the last part.
《その瞬間を たまたま
オジーが見ただけだ》
((あっ ムッタ))
Oh, Mutta.
《俺は記憶力も冷静な判断力も
何ひとつ発揮していない！➡
This had nothing to do with memory or cool judgment!
な～んにもしてないんだよ！
本当は！》
I didn't do jack!
いやぁ ムッタさん
素晴らしいよ！
Yes, that was very impressive, Mutta.
一体 どんな気持ちで
犯人に立ち向かったんだい？
How did you feel when you were facing the criminal?
《正直に…本当のこと言った方が
いいよな やっぱ…｡➡
I probably should tell them the truth...
みんな どう思うんだろうな》
What will they think?
え～ みなさま…｡
Uh, everyone...
発表します…｡
I have an announcement to make.
And when you consider the range of motion...
(日々人)それから 稼動域について
なんだけど…｡
(バディ)来てみろよ ヒビト！➡
Come over here, Hibito.
ムッタがテレビに出てるぜ！
Mutta's on TV.
Huh?
[TV](司会者)
目が見えてないにもかかわらず➡
Despite being unable to see,
記憶を頼りに店内を駆け抜け➡
Mutta used his memory as he dashed through the restaurant,
見事 犯人を倒したムッタ！
まさに宇宙飛行士の…｡
and took down the criminal!
He is a model astronaut!
(ｼﾞｪﾆﾌｧｰ)あらら～｡一夜にして
あの子 有名人？
Oh, my...
He's become famous overnight?
こりゃ なんか裏があるわね｡
There must be another side to this.
Ah.
ふっ…ははははっ！あははは！
どうした ヒビト？
What is it, Hibito?
いや…ははっ
ムッちゃんの表情 見たら➡
Well,
after seeing Mu's face, I can guess what really happened.
なんとな～く
事件の状況が見えてきてさ｡
(職員)お～い ヒビト！表に
取材陣が殺到してるって｡
Hey, Hibito.
A bunch of reporters want to see you.
ええ!?俺だけ？
What? Just me?
そりゃそうだろ｡
ムッタのことに決まってる｡
Of course. They want to ask you about Mutta.
行ってやれよ｡
Go on.
お前の兄貴なんだからな｡
He's your brother, after all.
しょうがねえな｡
じゃ ちょっと…➡
I suppose that's true.
In that case...
六太の愉快な昔話でも
してこようかな｡
I'll go and tell them some funny stories about Mutta.
[TV]え…あ…そう それです｡
Uh, y-yes.
That's right...
《ムッちゃん 顔かて～な｡
もうちょい ほぐせよ｡➡
Mu's stiff as a board.
He needs to lighten up.
昔みたいに何か面白いこと言って
みんなを喜ばせてやれよ》
Say something funny and make everyone laugh, like you used to do.
いや～いい番組だったな ムッタ｡
Man,
that was an excellent show, Mutta.
特に最後のコメントは良かったぞ｡
I especially loved your final comment.
もう何て言ったか忘れたよ｡
I've already forgotten what I said.
((え～みなさま
聞いて頂けますでしょうか))
Uh, please hear me out, everyone.
《本当は転んだだけなんだ
本当のことを言うんだ…》
I just tripped and fell.
I'll tell them the truth.
((本当は あの時 目が…見…))
Actually, I could...
((ウホンッ！本当に目が
見えてなくてですね➡
Actually, I couldn't see a thing.
それはもう真っ暗なのか
真っ白なのか わからないほどに))
I couldn't tell if it was dark or light.
((正直 一瞬パニｯクになりました｡
一瞬ですけどね｡➡
To be honest, I panicked for a second there.
Only for a second, though.
だけど その時
思い出したんです｡➡
But that was when I remembered...
弟 日々人も
今頃 目隠しをして…➡
My brother Hibito was probably blindfolded,
孤独の暗闇に立ち向かっている
ということを！))
training in total darkness.
((すると 勇気が湧いてきました…
俺は１人じゃないんだと｡➡
That gave me the courage I needed.
I wasn't alone.
弟のおかげです))
It was all thanks to my brother!
Wow...
((そして
ある言葉が浮かびました｡➡
And then, one word came to mind...
正義です！))
Justice!
((その言葉の前で私は
ウソをつけませんでした｡➡
I could never lie, not in the face of justice.
私が あの犯人に
向かって行ったのは…➡
I took down the criminal,
この国の ひとつの正義を
貫き通すためです！))
to uphold the justice of this country!
(観客)((素敵～！ムッター！))
That's wonderful, Mutta!
(観客)((こっち向いて～！))
Look over here, Mutta!
《何が…何が｢正義の前で
ウソはつけない｣だよ！➡
Never lie...
Never lie in the face of justice?
｢美人の前で格好つけたい｣が
本音だろ！》
I just wanted to look good in front of pretty girls!
Hey, Ozzy.
なあ オジー｡
To be honest,
実は本当のこと言うとさ
犯人 倒したのって…➡
the one who took down the criminal
アポなんだよね｡
was Apo.
今は犯人の記憶が
飛んでるみたいだけど➡
That guy might not be able to remember anything now,
もし 思い出されたら…➡
but if he ever does remember, everyone will know it wasn't me.
俺がやってないことが
ばれちゃうよ｡
ハハハッ｡ワシが犯人なら➡
If I were that criminal,
思い出しても｢犬にやられた｣
なんて言わないけどな｡
I'd never tell anyone that I was thwarted by a dog.
ワシもホントのこと言うとな
実は全部見てた｡
Truth be told, I saw everything that happened.
えっ？…えええっ!?
Eh? What?!
だが 根も葉もないウソを
ついたとは思ってない｡
But I didn't tell a single lie.
実際ムッタは あの時
アポを助けに走っただろ？
You were running to save Apo.
あれは勇気だ｡
君の言った｢正義｣のな｡➡
That took courage... To uphold your own justice.
監視カメラには
煙でアポは映ってなかった｡➡
The smoke obscured Apo from the security camera,
どう見ても ムッタが犯人を
やっつけたように映ってたんだ｡
so you appeared to be attacking the criminal.
あんなのを見てしまったら
ムッタが上手くいく方に➡
After seeing that footage, I wanted to bet that you'd come out on top.
賭けずにはいられない｡
《ギャンブラーめ！》
Stupid gambler...
君はチャンスを逃がさなかった｡
And you didn't waste the chance.
えらいぞ ムッタ｡君もなかなかの
勝負師だ｡見てみろ｡
Good job, Mutta.
You're a competitor.
Look.
ウフフ ハーイ！
Hi!
ムッター！
握手して～！
Mutta!
Can I shake your hand?
いいか ムッタ
これは信じていい｡
Listen to me, Mutta.
This is a fact.
｢運も実力のうち｣だ｡
Luck is what you make of it.
That was when...
《この瞬間 いや正確には
ｱﾒﾘｶ女性と握手した瞬間か…➡
Well, technically,
it was when I shook hands with the American girl
｢運も実力のうち｣という表現が
何とも都合よ～く➡
that I fully understood the meaning of what Ozzy had said
されど いい感じに
私を納得させてくれた｡➡
about luck being what you make of it.
これでよし
万事ＯＫ！》
This is good.
Everything worked out!
Astronaut Nanba
Hibito's Brother, Mutta, Successfully
Mutta's become a hero.
すごいヒーローになってますね
六太君｡
なすだ
(茄子田)あ ねえねえ みんな｡あの
昨日のニュース見た？
Oh... Hey, everyone.
Did you watch the news yesterday?
あ 茄子田理事長｡
Ah, Director Nasuda...
そうそう 彼 彼｡
南波六太君｡
Yes, about him, Nanba Mutta.
私もねえ 彼はいいなぁと
思ってたんだよね～ うん｡
I rather liked him, yes...
彼 もちろん通ってるよね？
二次ぐらいね｡ねえ？
He passed the exam, yes?
The second round? Yes?
Right?
(二村)え…え～っと…｡
(茄子田)いやいや 通ってるんなら
いいんだよ うん｡
Uh...
As long as he passed.
Yes, I'll be busy with interviews and the like for a while.
いや～ これから取材やら何やらで
忙しくなっちゃうね～｡
It's such a pain.
ホント困っちゃうよね～｡
美容院に行っとこうね｡
I'll have to drop by the salon.
《モジャ君
やってくれるじゃないか》
Afro made it happen.
Itou Serika
じゃあ ３列目の左から４番目は？
Next, third row, fourth card from the left.
ハートの２｡
Two of hearts.
ふん！
Hmph.
すごい！また正解だ｡
よく覚えられるな｡
Impressive. Right again.
You actually memorized them all?
Man, I didn't expect this skill to be a hit with astronauts...
いや～ こんな芸が飛行士達に
ほめられるなんて ヘヘッ｡
何かトリックがあるんでしょ？
ねえ それとも変に運がいいとか？
You must be using some trick.
Or are you just lucky?
フフフ…ジェニファーちゃん
もし これが運だとしてもね➡
Jennifer, if you're saying this is luck,
それも俺の実力なわけだよ｡
な～に アンタ急に
自信づいちゃって｡➡
I'm the one putting that luck to use.
What's this?
Suddenly found your confidence?
さては テレビに出たからって
調子ぶっこいてるな｡➡
Guess you've gotten cocky, after your TV appearance.
レプリカのジャンプスーツまで
買っちゃって｡
You even bought a replica jumpsuit.
フフーン 何とでも言ってくれよ｡
You can say whatever you want.
ムッちゃ～ん！ちょっと…｡
Mu!
Over here!
な～に～？
What's up?
おもしれえヤツだな ムッタって｡
ヒビトとは
全然違うタイプだけどな｡
Mutta's an interesting guy.
But he's completely different from Hibito.
母ちゃん達から ビデオメール
来てんだよ 俺のパソコンに｡
Mom and Dad sent me a video message
on my computer.
件名に｢ムッタ２次試験結果報告｣
って書いてあんだ｡
The subject is "Mutta's Second Exam Results."
Huh?!
ここで みんなと一緒に見る？
それとも１人でコッソリ見る？
We could all watch it together here.
Or do you want to watch it alone?
ムッタの試験の結果報告だそうだ｡
結果がどうなるにしろ➡
This message concerns Mutta's selection exam results.
Regardless of the result,
これは１人の男の
節目となる瞬間だ｡
this is a turning point in his life.
みんなで見守ってやろう｡
Let's support him.
[VTR](南波母)
どうも～！
２人とも元気してる？➡
Hello!
Are you boys doing okay?
父さんと母さんは
元気モリモリで～す！➡
Your mom and dad are doing great!
ムッちゃん あんたアメリカで
何やらかしたか知らんけど➡
Mu, I'm not sure what you've been up to in America, but everyone's talking about you.
えらい騒ぎになってるようね｡
まあ 生きててよかったわ｡➡
Well, I'm glad you're alive.
それはさておき お父さんのﾓﾉﾏﾈの
レパートリーが２個増えました｡
Anyway, your dad's learned two new impersonations.
[VTR](南波父)帰ったら見せてやる｡
[VTR]お楽しみにぃ～！
I'll show you when you get back.
So exciting!
何？訳してくれよ｡何だって？
いや…父がモノマネの…｡
訳さなくていいよ！
What? Can you translate for us?
What'd she say?
Oh, our dad learned...
You don't need to translate that part!
[VTR]あと…それから これ｡➡
Oh,
one more thing...
ジャクサ
え～ ＪＡＸＡから通知が来たので
見せま～す｡ねっ｡
I'll show you the letter we received from JAXA.
Okay?
[VTR]母さん それじゃ
見えないんじゃないか？
[VTR]あ そうね｡どう？➡
Hey, I don't think they can read it.
Oh, you're right.
How's that?
You have passed the second exam.
これで見えるかしら？
おめでとう！
Can you read it now?
Congratulations!
通過だ！
≪お～！≫
(カレン)おめでとう ムッタ！
You passed!
Yes!
Congrats, Mutta!
≪素晴らしい！≫
≪よくやったな ムッタ！≫
Way to go, Mutta!
やったな ムッちゃん！
You did it, Mu!
次は最終選考だな ムッタ｡
One more round of exams to go, Mutta!
ちょっとトイレ行ってくる｡
I need to use the restroom.
[VTR]という訳で 母さん達は
お祝いのケーキを食べま～す｡
So we're going to eat a cake to celebrate!
イエス!!だぁ～っ！
Right on!
うお～っ！よしよしよし…！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
いやあ 飲んだなぁ 日々人｡
Man, I drank too much, Hibito.
風呂入って寝よ～｡
明日は帰国だ｡
I'm taking a bath and going to bed.
I've gotta head home tomorrow.
ムッちゃん お土産
トランクに入れとくからな｡
Mu, I put the souvenirs in your suitcase.
ウィー サンキュー｡
Okay, thank you.
ブライアン…
うちの兄貴が また一歩進んだよ｡
Brian, my brother's taken another step forward.
面白くなってきた！
It's starting to get fun!
This morning, when I saw this message, I was super-excited.
《私は今朝 このメールに気づき
大興奮し➡
そして みんなと
審査結果を見た時も➡
And when I was watching the video e-mail with everyone,
I held on to the message, to bring me luck.
このメールを お守りとして
握り締めていた》
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
何回見てもいいっ!!
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
I'll never get sick of reading it.
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
Itou Serika
It's been a while.
It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
I was so surprised
when I saw you on the
news today!
As someone who
｢南波さん お久しぶりです｡
伊東せりかです｡➡
"It's been a while, Nanba.
This is Itou Serika.
今日のﾆｭｰｽで南波さんのご活躍が
報道されているのを見て➡
I was so surprised when I saw you on the news today!
びっくりしました！
南波さんの勇気ある行動に➡
As someone who also aims to be an astronaut,
同じ宇宙飛行士を目指す者として
尊敬のまなざしです｡➡
I admire your courage to act.
そろそろ審査結果が
送られてくる頃ですね｡➡
We should be receiving our results soon.
お互い まだ結果は
わかりませんが➡
Neither of us knows how we did yet,
今度は３次試験で お会いできる
ことになればいいですね｡➡
but I hope we'll be meeting up in the third exam.
伊東せりか｣｡
Itou Serika."
な～んて素敵なメールだ…｡
It's such a beautiful message.
永久保存だ 永久保存！家のPCにも
バックアップを送っとこっと｡
Move to the permanent folder!
I'll send a copy to my home computer, as backup!
《せりかさんのおかげで
通りましたよ 俺！》
Serika's the reason I passed!
ヘヘヘ…日々人め｡
Silly Hibito...
相変わらず 隠し場所が
中学レベルでらっしゃる｡
You've been hiding your stuff in the same places since middle school.
どれどれ 兄がチェックしてやる｡
Okay, your brother's going to see what's inside.
Hmm?
お…お前…｡
Wait...
なんだよ これ…｡
What is this?
まぐれでも３次まで
いったんだから頑張んなさいよ！
気をつけろよ ムッタ｡
Fluke or not, you made it to the third exam, so work hard!
Be careful, Mutta.
ああ！日々人にも頑張れって
言っといて｡
ＯＫ！
Yeah, tell Hibito to work hard.
Okay!
《私は帰り際 何より重たい荷物を
頭の中に積んでしまっていた》
As I headed home,
I carried some heavy baggage inside.
The stars I admired were too bright for me
so I quietly closed my eyes
I have faith in you, as you stand alone, full of doubts
I'm right here, next to you
Come now, take my hand and hold it tight
If you do, we will always
have hope, shine with light
and overcome whatever we might face
Do you see how wonderful this world is
and how our future unfolds?
Even the tears we shed and could not put into words
will one day dry up, I am sure
One by one the smiles spread
and ascend towards the starlit sky
＜私が見つけてしまった
日々人からの手紙＞
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#09 Individual Resolve
I accidentally came across Hibito's letters.
＜それは なんと
私や両親に宛てた遺書だった＞
They were wills,
addressed to our parents and me.
＜｢ムッちゃんへ
一つ お願いがある｡➡
"Dear Mu,
I have a request to make.
もし 俺が死んだら…｣＞
If I die..."
＜あの日々人が
こんな覚悟をしてたなんて…＞
I never knew Hibito was prepared to die.
＜いや 日々人だけじゃない｡
父ちゃんも 母ちゃんも➡
No, it wasn't just Hibito...
Mom and Dad were prepared, as well.
実は あれで覚悟ができてるんだ＞
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Individual Resolve".
＜俺にも その時が来た＞
It's my turn now!
パンパカパーン！
今週の➡
This Week's Space Photo
Visit the official website (uchukyodai.com) for more details.
This week's space photo!
宇宙写真です｡
すっげえ！
Awesome!